In this segment we're going to be talking about jump roping and how jump roping is effective for boxing and how boxing is affected by jump roping.
We're going to be talking about the different types of jump ropes.
We're going to talk about plastic speed ropes.
We're going to be talking about some heavier leather jump ropes with the way it handles.
We're going to be talking about how to determine the length of the jump rope that you would need.
We're going to cover a little bit about the actual proper footwear to wear for jump roping.
We're going to be talking about some basic moves for jump roping and we're going to have one of our boxing students show you the basic moves and also some of the more advanced moves.
Some of the other things we're going to be covering are the different constructions of the jump ropes themselves and how to adjust them if you need to adjust them.
The place of the jump rope, you should be jumping like on a jump rope mat for instance or in the mat in the ring.
You should try to stay off concrete for instance and things like that.
So as we expand upon the different clips, we're going to mention more detail on the jump roping.